if I'm trying to cover three different
stories of travel in one video it's not
gonna go perfectly so I just need to
come to Kurtz with that I don't have to
do this yet again so when I was 16 I
went to Germany on an exchange
I had a exchange student come here for
three months and my high school had two
other exchange students than the three
of us Canadians went over for three
months to visit them in their respective
cities so I was the only one in the
small city my exchange student was from
town really but going to Germany it was
my first time on a plane it was my first
time experiencing true culture shock and
being surrounded by people who didn't
speak the language that I spoke and
although nearly everyone did speak
English they couldn't speak English when
they were in groups they were speaking
German I got to walk on streets that
experience World War two I got to
interact with history and history has
never been my favorite subject but there
was something about being there being
present when we were learning that back
home in social studies class that was
different
seeing buildings and pictures of the
main bomba seeing the Berlin Wall and
the way that their atrocity of the
Holocaust and World War two was taught
to children in grade five we were
learning about it because I took English
classes with the grade fives because
they were learning English I was
learning in German scene I remember they
had these weird these weird skateboards
that had a pivot in the middle and
they'd had them for decades and they
could go up hills in them and I was like
well why don't we have these like it's
only across an ocean why don't these
exist back where we were from I feel
like kids would would like these and
just not realizing just those little
things like oh this is different not
being able to eat peanut-butter trying
to make rice krispies square doesn't not
being able to find white marshmallow as
we had to use colored ones and they were
from like an American army base store
there were American army bases we're
sneaking onto one in reading reading
books about some apocalypse well I was
like in this deserted barracks it was it
was interesting I spent three months
skipping school and wandering through
this small town by myself because I felt
out of place in this school I saw what
some classes but the majority of the
time was spent reading and being by
myself and experiencing the this righty
letters back and forth with my friends
but it would take like three weeks to
ask a question and get a response from
them and our letters would would pass
each other in the mail in flight and so
my friend my two best friends were
breaking apart while asking me for
advice on this and I wasn't able to
respond and we'd have the odd
conversation but with the time
difference and with the expense of long
distance it was the first time I
experienced email I used my exchange
dad's email to email back and forth with
my boyfriend at the time having a
boyfriend when I well I was that
following we had like just started
dating it was a very interesting
experience going on a German exchange
one I wouldn't change for the world it
gave me so much compassion for people
who are forced to move to a different
country and not speak the language
because although it was lonely not being
able to speak German for three months if
I lived there permanently I would have
had to learn it and whatever bits I
could put together would have eventually
been what I was able to communicate
I just took three months off of having
in-depth deep conversations except for I
didn't because I got to have a week in
Berlin with the other exchange students
I got to have they were Irish not
exchange students but an Irish class I
think there was like 20 of them that
came to the small town I was in for a
week I said I got to like live history
and learned that I German it's not an
easy language for me to learn then kiss
I hadn't learned that lesson yet that
language is not my strong point I
volunteered to go to Costa Rica in
between my high school
and university which ended up taking
having to take four years off between
the two which I'll cover at my
university video so I went to Costa Rica
when I was 20 thinking in whatever way I
was going to save them but I was gonna
volunteer my time we were gonna build
hospitals at schools and is that this
gonna be amazing we had two different
placements with but we were at the same
group of people Wow
there was Australians that came
Canadians that came and then a handful
of the local Costa Ricans Tico's
Antigua's and when we got there we got
to choose which project we were on like
we got to say which one we wanted to be
on and our group ended up being all the
people who said put me wherever you want
me because it was probably the least
attractive of the groups of the projects
but we got the best people on it for
that very reason it was like the people
were like wherever fate wants me is
where I will go we went to this small
town that was brand new and we were
trying to build a school we didn't have
that we didn't have the equipment like
it wasn't arrived yet so we basically
kind of did all of these odd jobs around
this town at one point we were picking
up litter Lord laughing at us and
throwing litter at us and like this town
wasn't connected because they were new
and yet at the same time there was this
private waterfall and we did finally
start building a school this in the
community came together and started
started helping with that and then we
traveled like four hours away it took us
an entire day to get there to this small
town where people had more of a
community they'd spent generations there
but the teenagers went away to school
the difference between just those two
placements with was huge but learning
how connected these people are and how
much they have to give each other was
meant when I got back from Costa Rica I
went through extreme reverse culture
shock I couldn't handle Canadian
sure it's like we're too busy it's too
chaotic we don't understand what what
like true beauty and community and
connection is and so although I was
planning on going to university one of
the people I'd went to Costa Rica with
was had applied for med school but had
not gotten in for several years so she
was going to go to Australia and so I
was like yes that's what I want to do I
don't wanna go to university I'm gonna
go with you to Australia what we can
visit the people we had also into Costa
Rica with and she ended up getting into
med school so she didn't go and I went
by myself to Australia
finally I went to a place where I do
speak the language but it was funny
because it was finally I was looking for
a cultural exchange and yet what I found
was like Canada culture but the opposite
like we're really cold they're really
hot we're both colonial well colonial
countries they like pushed out and have
horrible history with the Aboriginal
people we have horrible history the
First Nations people like I live by
Whistler where a lot of Australians
common ski and I was like hanging out
and Bondi Beach and the places a little
further so sorry North South would be a
little warmer new runs the beaches were
right hang out for a few weeks and so I
wasn't really in party mode but I was on
this like party bus and spending a lot
of time I myself but I'd kind of go in
and out of like I'd stay with one group
for a while and then continue on and I
was really hate like it was it didn't
make sense for me to go to Australia
like I said I was finally looking for a
cultural experience and everyone spoke
English and it was again I wouldn't
change it for the world and glad I went
there at that time well I was there I
applied to university back home and got
in and it was travelling by myself but
speaking the language and all three of
those experiences I mean I love
travelling but I don't do small
traveling I went to Germany for three
months and came back on speaking German
I went to Costa Rica for three months
and came back no speaking Spanish and I
tried hard to learn Spanish and Spanish
is someone
easier language learned in German then I
went to Australia and I wasn't there a
new language but I just followed animals
around I'm just like okay gurus that's
what I was there to do I went to hang
out near the river for a day all by
myself to and stayed in a small
town to find platypi
whatever the total of that is I saw
their bubbles but I didn't see them and
so that is my travel video I went to
Germany when I was 16 I turned 20 in
Costa Rica and I turned 21 in Australia
and I haven't really been traveling
since besides going to visit my sister
in California so that was half of my
lifetime ago